WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
JEFF:
36 days ago,
18 former castaways
came together
off the coast of Panama
under full military escort.
They were the best of the best,
the All-Stars,
returning to play
the ultimate game
one more time.
TOM:
This ain't a little boys' game.
This is for the big boys.
( whooping )
JEFF:
They were split
into three tribes
and marooned
with only one machete
in the harsh jungles of Panama.
Everything was heightened.
The survival...
I'm running out of steam.
...the strategy...
RICHARD:
Yeah, I think I could start
the fire without even blinking.
But they don't need
to know that.
( laughs )
...and the suspicion.
ROB:
I don't trust
any of you.
I don't trust any of you!
ROB:
Nobody trusts
anybody, do you understand?
Still, alliances formed
immediately.
Me and you ought
to think about
an alliance.
You're a man
of your word, too,
from what I know of you.
So what do you think,
you want to make
an alliance, cover
our own asses?
I don't know if I can
take you seriously or not.
Go!
The competition was fierce
at the challenges,
because the All-Stars
had a lot to prove.
JEFF:
Chapera-- the first tribe
to win immunity!
( cheering )
( thunder crashing )
In the beginning, it appeared
the former winners
would be the targets, when Tina
was the first All-Star
voted out.
Tina, the tribe has spoken.
But Rudy, the 75-year-old
former Navy Seal,
was the next to go.
Then Jenna Morasca
surprised everyone
when she quit the game
to return home
to her sick mother.
Due to someone who's very ill,
I need to...
pull myself out of the game.
Jenna, we're thinking about you.
Thanks.
( thunder crashing )
The elements were relentless,
and the adventure became
the most difficult ever.
( crying ):
It's not worth it.
But the true danger
proved to be betrayal.
As long as I have your assurance
on this, then I'm...
You want to
shake on it?
When Rob Cesternino,
one of the most strategic
players in Survivor history,
was blindsided
at Tribal Council, it was clear
that the game was on
in a big way.
Rob, the tribe has spoken.
On day 15,
three tribes became two
when the ailing Saboga Tribe
was absorbed
by the Mogo Mogo
and Chapera Tribes.
Saboga finishes last, and Saboga
will soon be no longer.
Though the former members
of Saboga were outnumbered
and as vulnerable as ever,
it was Richard Hatch,
the first-ever Survivor winner,
who was voted out.
I've been bamboozled!
Rich...
the tribe has spoken.
With Boston Rob
leading the way,
the Chapera Tribe proved to be
the powerhouse
at the challenges.
Wow!
And Rupert and Jenna
joined Rob and Amber
in an alliance of four.
Once it gets to the
final four, then we can...
we can, you know, every
man for themselves.
Things at Chapera
seemed to be on solid ground,
but the tribe had a setback
when Sue suddenly quit the game
under a cloud
of personal controversy.
I was violated, humiliated,
dehumanized,
and totally spent, Jeff,
and I'm done
with this ... game!
But still Chapera pushed on,
and the unstoppable tribe
won the next two
immunity challenges...
JEFF:
Chapera... wins reward
and immunity!
( cheering )
...sending Mogo Mogo to
the next two Tribal Councils,
where Colby and Ethan
were voted out.
The tribe has spoken.
At Chapera, strategy
turned into romance
for Rob and Amber.
AMBER:
Flirting was a huge strategy
in the beginning,
but then I got caught up in it,
and feelings, you know, emerged.
ROB:
Amber and I have been fooling
around a little bit out here.
I'm definitely attracted
to her.
It'd be nice to have
a million dollars
and take the girl away, too.
JEFF:
On day 22, everyone was hit
with a big surprise.
All right, drop your buffs.
( groans )
It was a tribal shuffle.
JEFF:
Boston Rob, you don't
look pleased at all.
Against all odds,
the tribes remain the same,
merely switching beaches
and tribe names.
Except for Amber,
who remained at Chapera
and became the only All-Star
to find herself
with new tribe mates.
This is crazy.
She was suddenly alone
and vulnerable in her own camp.
AMBER:
I definitely feel
like I'm the one
who got screwed
in this whole situation.
ROB:
I don't really care that
the other team has our camp.
What aggravates me is,
they got my girl over there.
JEFF:
When the new Mogo Mogo Tribe
won the next
immunity challenge,
Rob approached Lex and made
a daring plea to save Amber.
If you can, if you can.
And Amber made her own plea
to Kathy.
Please, Kathy,
keep me in the game.
Vote for Jerri.
At Tribal Council,
Lex and Kathy came through.
They granted Rob the favor
and spared Amber.
Ninth person voted out
of Survivor: All-Stars...
Jerri.
And Jerri paid the price.
On day 26, the two tribes
( cheering )
finally merged.
At the new Chaboga Mogo Tribe,
Lex looked for reassurance
from Rob.
If I get a sense that,
you know, I'm gonna
end up getting
the, you know, double-cross,
get a knife in my back
next Tribal Council,
I certainly won't be happy
about that.
I won't stick a knife
in your back, man.
I ain't gonna do that.
ROB:
What, "Make the deal,
save Amber and I'm gonna
help you later on"?
You guys didn't really
believe that, did you?
JEFF:
Rob confronted Lex
and told him the deal was off.
Make no mistake
about it, Lex,
the word I gave you was that
if I can take care of you,
I will.
I'm sorry, I cannot.
You have more allegiance to them
than you got to me.
You're breaking
my heart.
I can't...
I can't even believe it.
JEFF:
The strategic favor
had backfired
and Lex was voted out...
making him the first member
of the jury.
Kathy was the next
to join the jury.
Then Alicia and Shii Ann.
Last week, the five remaining
members of Chaboga Mogo
competed for a car
at the reward challenge.
Rob won and chose
to take Amber with him
to an island drive-in movie.
When they arrived, things got
even better for Amber.
One of the added benefits
of being selected
by Boston Rob--
something for you, Amber.
Are you serious?!
The two kicked back
and enjoyed the movie
and their first romantic date.
Upon returning to camp,
Amber told the others
about her new car.
I had the choice
whether or not to tell people,
but I felt that
holding that back from them
just wasn't me.
JEFF:
And Rupert and Tom
had had enough
of the power couple.
Take that damn
couple and break
that couple apart.
TOM:
If I get Tom in
with Jenna and I,
we three would put
Rob and Amber
out of this game.
JEFF:
But Rob, sensing trouble,
orchestrated a fight
between Rupert and Tom.
ROB:
He keeps telling me
that you keep saying
you want to vote me out.
If he tells you that,
then he's a lying
son of a bitch.
You've been talking about
getting rid of everybody, Tom,
behind everybody's back
and now I'm the bad guy?
ROB:
The reason I did this
was to get them
at each other's throats,
so that
neither of them
will have enough sense
to try to get me and Amber off.
JEFF:
At the immunity challenge,
Rob walked away
with the necklace once again.
JEFF:
Boston Rob wins immunity!
But he was worried
about Amber being outnumbered.
ROB:
The only way I don't hold
the power is if Rupert,
Jenna and Big Tom all team up
and vote Amber off.
JEFF:
Rob and Amber looked
for reassurance from Big Tom.
Why would you think I went
with Rupert and Jenna?
I don't know,
why you been feeding them stuff
for the last two weeks,
telling them
you want to get rid of me?
Let's make up our mind,
because when you tell me,
that's what I'm putting
on that card.
ROB:
That's it.
Let's do it.
AMBER:
It's Jenna.
The deal was made
to vote Jenna out.
But at Tribal Council,
Big Tom was betrayed.
Big Tom, the tribe
has spoken.
I heard it.
Big Tom was not happy.
Now only four remain.
Rupert, Boston Rob,
Amber and Jenna.
Tonight they will compete
in their final
immunity challenges.
Two will go on
to face the jury;
one will outlast all the rest
and become the sole
All-Star Survivor.
Subrip: btf
btf@freemail.hu
RUPERT:
We just got back
from day 36's Tribal Council,
where we voted Big Tom's butt
out of here.
What was that glare
as he walked out?
RUPERT:
He was looking at his, uh...
ROB:
You can tell
when someone's lying.
He lied right to my face,
like, five times.
JENNA:
It was an honest
and hurtful Tribal Council.
And now there are four torches
left up there.
It started out with 18
of the best survivors
to ever play this game,
and it's down to four,
and I'm one of them.
How'd that happen?
RUPERT:
I'm going to take that
down to the creek.
JENNA:
Okay.
ROB:
So, here's the thing,
me and Amber talked about it,
and it's completely up to you,
and I'm not gonna try
to influence you
one way or the other,
but all I'm gonna say is,
you have no chance
to beat Rupert.
If you want to take a shot
with me and Amber
in the final three,
then you can take
your own destiny
in your own hands.
I mean, like, you don't
even have to tell us.
We'll find out
whenever...
Yeah, we'll find out
at the vote.
( insects chirping )
AMBER:
Little did we know
that we were gonna be
woken up today
by Jeff pulling up in a boat
carrying a huge basket.
Want to give me a hand?
Take one side.
Sure.
AMBER:
I got a little nervous
at first.
I was thinking,
maybe, oh, gosh,
this is our challenge--
what are we gonna have to do?
I brought you guys gifts
fitting for a Final Four.
Let me show you.
( cheering )
You've got everything
you need for bacon, eggs,
pancakes...
( Rob cheers )
Pancakes!
Fresh fruit, orange juice,
champagne for mimosas.
Champagne!
In addition,
the top of this is also...
a scrapbook.
So, you have a camera.
So you can take pictures
during the day,
make up your scrapbook.
JEFF:
Does that look good?
The Final Four.
RUPERT:
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Enjoy!
Thank you, Jeff!
AMBER:
Breakfast is my favorite meal
of the day.
So this meal is huge out here.
ROB ( laughs ):
Guys, we made it 37 days.
Whatever happens
tonight happens,
and, uh, good luck
to everybody.
RUPERT:
Good luck to us all.
ALL:
Cheers.
ROB:
The four people
that are in the Final Four
are two distinct groups of two.
There's no chance myself
and Amber are gonna break.
I think it's a toss-up--
Jenna may...
turn on Rupert.
It may come down
to a purple rock.
JENNA:
I've been thinking about
this whole purple
rock thing.
So far...
like, the game has gone
so well for all of us.
JENNA:
I'm very concerned
with the tiebreaker situation.
What would happen is, whoever
has immunity has immunity.
And then the other three
have to reach into a bag--
there's two white rocks
and one purple one.
The person who gets the purple
rock is out of the game.
I don't want it
to come down
to a frickin' rock.
I know.
That's not what we played for.
AMBER:
We knew it was gonna
come down to a purple rock,
so we gave her the option
of voting out Rupert tonight.
JENNA:
Why don't you guys
just keep up your end
and vote Rupert?
We will.
JENNA:
Strategically,
I came out here to win,
and this is the way
to do it for me;
it gets me
one step closer.
I didn't come 37 days
to reach into a bag and let...
a color decide my fate,
so I'm taking fate
in my own hands.
AMBER:
Is that breakfast
I smell?
Yes, ma'am!
JENNA:
All I've been craving
is a pancake,
and it was the best...
I, like,
ate tiny little bites.
It's better than I have
at home.
Oh, my God!
Mmm.
RUPERT:
This morning's breakfast
is good-bye to one of us.
Somebody is leaving tonight.
Boy, I hope it's not me.
All right, let's get to
today's immunity challenge.
Boston Rob, give it up.
Immunity, back up for grabs.
For today's immunity challenge,
we have constructed
a giant maze.
On my go, you will race
from the center of the maze
to eight different points
within the maze.
At each point,
you'll find a ladder rung.
Untie it, bring it back
to the center.
Along the way, you're going
to encounter various obstacles
blocking your path.
And you're going see the same
obstacle more than once.
The trick is don't get confused.
Once you've gathered all eight,
you'll assemble your ladder,
climb to the top of the tower.
First person to the top
of the tower wins.
Make sense?
We'll draw colors.
Wait for my go.
Here we go, guys.
For immunity and a guaranteed
spot in the Final Three.
Survivors, ready... Go!
Everybody off.
Jenna hits a dead end.
Boston Rob working on
the crawl-through.
Amber out of the other
crawl-through.
Rupert makes his way
through the ropes.
Amber finds her first rung.
Jenna working her way through
the ropes, getting tangled up.
Boston Rob has his first rung.
Rupert finds his first rung.
Amber still making her way
back to the center
with her first rung.
Jenna untying her first rung.
Boston Rob has his first rung.
Amber's in with one.
Rupert's in with one.
Everybody has one except Jenna.
Jenna with her first.
Everybody has one rung.
Rob and Amber going through
the ropes together.
Jenna making her way
through the walk-through.
Amber and Rob both
getting a second rung.
Jenna has her second rung.
Rob passes Amber in the ropes.
Jenna's back with her second,
Rupert's back with his second.
Boston Rob back with his second,
and Amber back with her second.
We're tied up, two rungs each.
Looking for a total of eight.
Rob on his third rung.
Jenna untying her third rung.
She's got to get back
to the center.
Boston Rob back with
his third rung.
Jenna with a third rung.
Amber with a third rung.
Rupert back with a third rung.
We're tied up,
everybody has three rungs.
Boston Rob with four rungs.
Jenna with four rungs.
Amber with four rungs.
Rupert with four rungs.
Everybody tied up.
Boston Rob quietly sneaks in
with his fifth rung.
He's got a lead.
Jenna with her fifth rung.
Boston Rob back in the center.
Amber with her fifth rung.
We're all tied up, five rungs.
Boston Rob going in circles.
Rupert untying his sixth rung.
Got to get back to the center.
Amber with her sixth rung.
Boston Rob coming back
the other way now.
Still going in circles.
Rupert closing the gap
with his sixth rung.
Jenna back with her sixth rung.
Boston Rob back
with his sixth rung.
Amber with her seventh.
Amber needs only one more rung.
Rupert with seven,
looking for his last rung.
Amber on her way back
with her last rung.
Rupert untying his.
Rob back with his seventh.
Amber has all eight pieces.
Amber assembling her ladder.
She's got two pieces
put together.
Three pieces.
She's got her fourth piece.
Fifth.
Amber very close.
She's climbing the ladder.
And with that...
Yes!
Amber wins immunity!
( screams )
Guaranteed Final Three!
Amber, come on down.
Put this on.
Boy, when you needed it,
you got it.
Nicely done.
Oh, my God.
You are safe tonight
at Tribal Council.
I've never worn this before.
Looks good.
I think so, too.
Amber is safe
at the vote tonight.
The other three of you are not.
Somebody is about to go home.
You have the afternoon
to figure that out.
I'll see you at Tribal.
Head on out.
We vote for Rob
and see what happens.
Yeah, I got a lot
to talk to you about.
What do you want
to talk to me about?
He came to me last night
and said there's no way
that they're going
to vote for each other,
"So, Jenna, why don't you
just take your chances
and vote Rupert?"
I debated it, kept throwing
the idea around, and...
I'm not.
I can't do it.
I would rather sit there and
pick a rock than give them
the smug satisfaction of knowing
that they're guaranteed
a spot.
RUPERT:
My fate rests on the honor
of a 26-year-old
single mama who really,
really wants to win badly.
ROB:
So how is everything
going to go down tonight?
Have you decided?
No.
Obviously, I have
a vested interest in it.
But, I mean, you can't
beat Rupert in the Final Two.
Yeah, but that's why it
might be worth it for me
to choose a rock
and then you're out
and it's me
that's in.
Maybe you, too.
Exactly.
Well, to me,
that's ridiculous...
Because you won't
do it against her.
That's my point.
There's a possibility
I could beat her.
There's no possibility
I could beat Rupert.
you could beat Rupert.
I disagree.
It's the difference
between maybe winning
the million or a 30% shot
at maybe going home.
JENNA:
Now I don't know.
I'm not letting Rob push me
into anything, but there is...
truth, I mean, I would be
in the Final Three.
I might go up against them
and beat them,
and then I've got
a million dollars.
Let's go spend
some time together.
This might be my last day here.
AMBER:
Don't be sad.
Yesterday, you're all
feeling confident...
Nah, I am, I'm
totally fine with it.
Today, you're not
feeling confident.
It's out of my hands.
There's nothing
I can do about it,
so I'm not going to worry
about it, you know?
Yeah.
If I do go tonight,
you better win.
Quit saying that.
No, you better.
You better.
I want you to
come with me.
This is so good.
The decision is still...
it's still a little up
in the air... to be honest.
RUPERT:
I can't see Jenna
going against me,
and I don't want to go
against Jenna.
She's just a little paranoid.
You got to let her alone.
She's just a young girl.
She's fine.
Either way,
I appreciate it.
I know.
I believe that she will
write Rob's name down.
The beginning-of-this-game
person Jenna would say...
"Don't let emotional attachment
get in the way
of your strategic
survival game."
What about you?
My emotions
control what I do.
In this game or
out of this game,
that's all I got
is who I am.
ROB:
Rupert's a very smart player.
I give him a lot of credit.
He's probably conned Jenna
into feeling bad about doing
anything but pulling a rock.
I've never been in so much
turmoil in my life.
I have the power tonight.
I really don't know
what I'm going to do...
until I get to Tribal Council.
It's really, really
a tough decision.
Now, bring in the members
of our jury--
Lex, Kathy, Alicia, Shii Ann...
Big Tom voted out
at the last Tribal Council.
So, let's get right into it.
At the last Tribal Council,
Big Tom clearly blindsided.
Jury reaction was pretty strong.
Did you see it, Jenna?
Yeah, I saw it, yeah.
Did it put anything
through your head,
because the power's
clearly shifted now.
Of course.
These are people
that we have voted out.
Facing them
is traumatic,
every single time
we come here.
Clearly, Big Tom had no idea
that he was about to go.
Boston Rob, here we are,
we're down to
a Final Five situation
and you betray somebody again,
knowing you need them
to get the money.
All I can say, Jeff, is
there's two sides
to every story.
And I say that with
100% conviction.
Amber, make the argument
that "It's not fair
"to judge me because
I voted you out.
That is part of the game."
In Australia, I had
an alliance, um...
or what I thought
was an alliance,
and I was somewhat
blindsided.
But when it
came down to it,
I actually ended up
voting for the person
who broke their
alliance with me.
And it was really hard for me
to cast that vote
because they hurt my feelings.
But then I also
had to remember
that I'm playing
the game of Survivor,
and it's "outwit,
outplay, outlast,"
and I felt that that person
truly outwitted me.
JEFF:
And it seems to me,
with each successive
Tribal Council,
the emotional wear and tear
on you guys increases.
Rupert, you and Jenna
have been pretty tight.
There's no mystery
that Boston Rob and Amber
have been pretty tight,
but there's always been
somebody else to vote out.
It's not the case anymore.
Today was a very tough day.
It was very high
and very low.
Coming home
without the necklace
and then being told
that the game might be
changing for you,
those were pretty big lows.
Jenna, fill in the blanks
for me.
Because what Rupert's saying
is he's either out,
or it's going to be a tie,
and he's going to
get a shot at fate.
Exactly.
It really is
a true toss-up,
because I truly
have a bond with Rupert.
This is a game
and I have to get myself
as far as I can, but then
do I put somebody
else's game at risk--
that I love--
out here?
And that's been resting
on my shoulders today.
So, Rupert, what it comes
down to for you, tonight,
from what I'm understanding,
is whether or not Jenna
is going
to put your name down
or Boston Rob's,
her only other option.
You know, everybody's got
to play the game how they play.
And that's okay.
But I hope that Jenna and I
would stand strong,
that we would force
the rock issue.
Amber, you have immunity.
Cannot vote for Amber.
It is time to vote.
Rupert, you're up.
I don't know what else to say.
I hope we both have two votes
and I hope we go into a tie.
You're a gentleman, buddy.
It's been a pleasure
playing the game with you.
I hope it's you tonight
and not me.
Thanks.
I still don't know.
I'll go tally the votes.
Once the votes are read,
the decision is final.
The person voted out
will be asked
to leave the Tribal Council area
immediately.
I'll read the votes.
First vote...
Rob.
Rupert.
One vote Rob, one vote Rupert.
Two votes Rupert.
One vote Rob.
The last vote...
The 15th person voted out
of Survivor All-Stars
and the sixth member
of our jury, Rupert.
Need to bring me your torch.
It's part of the game.
Rupert, the tribe
has spoken.
It's time for you to go.
Well, you've survived
another vote,
made it through another day.
We are now down to three people,
two Tribal Councils...
one winner.
Grab your torches.
Head back to camp.
Good night.
RUPERT:
I am a little angry at Jenna.
Greed won out over friendship.
Almost disgusted me.
There's not one person
in this game
that can say I lied to them,
that I played conniving.
I did my best.
I honestly had a very,
very good experience
with Survivor All-Stars.
JENNA:
I love Rupert, but you know,
I couldn't let my whole
game be put into a bag
and roll the dice on
whether I'd get a rock
that would send me
home tonight.
Mm-hmm.
Right.
Not when I still had fate
in my hands that
I could work.
Regardless...
regardless of your decision,
whatever it was,
I respect the fact that,
you know,
you made it on your own.
JENNA:
Yeah.
And that's the most
important thing.
Ooh!
Hey, Jeff.
Morning.
Good morning.
What are you guys
doing up so early?
We're the Final Three.
We couldn't really sleep
too much.
Beautiful moon.
It is.
I got my girls.
Life is good.
Well, day 38 is here.
Today you'll take part
in your final rite of passage.
We brought along a canoe.
You'll take this map.
You'll follow it to an area
where you will find
an array of body paints
and jewelry used and worn
by a local and fiercely-
independent tribe of Indians,
the Cunas.
You'll adorn your bodies
as you see fit,
then you'll set out on foot.
As you walk, you will come along
the torches
of your fellow tribe members
who have been voted out.
Take a moment.
Think about the impact they
had on you and on the game.
When you reach the last torch,
I'll be waiting for you there
to guide you through
your final immunity challenge.
I encourage you
to embrace this day.
You're never going
to be back here again.
Thanks, Jeff.
I'll see you at the other side.
Grab the paddles.
ROB:
Oh... there.
Oh, wow!
Oh, my gosh.
This is so awesome.
JENNA:
This is awesome.
Look at these.
AMBER:
It's that one.
You girls look pretty.
( chuckles )
TINA:
I'd do this again
because it's part of my being.
This was such
a life-expanding adventure.
I think I would have regretted
if I didn't come,
and I don't want any regrets
in my life.
75 years old.
If I were military,
I'd salute you.
RUDY:
The second time around,
I was three years slower,
for one thing.
And there's a lot
of cut-throating
going on out there.
And I should have known better.
JENNA M.:
I've already played this game,
and I've already won.
I'll look back on this
just like I did the Amazon,
and be glad that I fought
through as much as I could.
( Rob chuckling )
He's not even here,
and he's making
us laugh.
I know, right?
ROB C.:
It's a little bit of
a humbling experience.
I thought that I might be,
in fact,
the greatest Survivor player
to ever play,
but I was a victim
of my own success, I think.
RICHARD:
One of the biggest things
that surprised me
about the entire
Survivor: All-Stars
was how tough it was.
Certainly more tough
than the original game
I played.
Either I'm getting older
or it's getting way,
way too tough for me.
SUE:
I was just totally exempt
from any energy or emotion.
I decided that I had to leave.
It takes too much emotion
to play this game.
COLBY:
I found patience this time
that I never knew I had.
The game required it,
my mental stability
required it,
and I was so proud to find it.
ETHAN:
In Africa, I didn't receive
one vote against me
the entire time
I was out there.
During All-Stars,
you know, it hurts.
And each time
you see your name,
you feel that little punch
in your gut.
I still want to be out there
playing the game.
AMBER;
The reason why I'm here
is 'cause the reason
why she's gone.
Thanks, Jerri.
JERRI:
I ask myself so many times
a day,
"Why would I want to put myself
through this again?"
I had no idea that it was going
to nearly break my spirit.
But it didn't.
LEX:
I broke the biggest promise
I made to myself
coming into this thing.
I mixed friendship
with the game.
The two cannot mix together.
And as soon as you allow
a little too much compassion
to show through,
you're setting yourself up
for disaster.
KATHY:
What I rely on is trust
and loyalty
and the better qualities
of life.
Maybe I just don't have it in
myself to make it all the way
to the million and lie.
ALICIA:
This time around,
I bit my tongue a lot more,
I walked away a lot more,
kept my mouth quiet.
I eased back
on the challenges a lot,
so that I didn't look
like such a threat.
And it got me six days further
into the game this time.
SHII ANN:
I've played with the best.
I beat my favorite players,
I beat them all.
And ultimately, it came down
to bad luck with the numbers.
Sometimes that's the way
the chips fall.
TOM:
Truly, I didn't consider
myself an All-Star.
For me, just to say that I was
in that group is a proud moment
for an old country boy like me.
AMBER:
I definitely consider
playing the game with him
as a huge honor.
RUPERT:
I came out here
to take care of myself
and everyone around me,
and I did.
I might not have won
one damn immunity challenge,
but I won a few rewards.
I enjoyed myself, I shared,
I cared and I actually had fun.
AMBER:
Walking by all the torches
made me feel proud
to be standing
where I was standing,
but also a little guilty,
knowing that I ended this game
for a lot of those people.
So, it was a little bit
bittersweet.
I'm feeling a little scared
and nervous...
and not really knowing
what's ahead.
At the end of the day,
one of us is going
to have immunity,
and one of us will not be
in the Final Two.
Well, welcome
to your final
immunity challenge.
Amber, I'll take
that back.
For the last time,
immunity is back up for grabs.
Today's immunity challenge
is very simple.
It's all about endurance.
How badly do you want it?
You will stand barefoot
on posts.
You'll have one hand
on the Immunity Idol,
and you'll stand there
as long as you can.
Here are the rules.
If either of your feet come off
of that post at any time
for any reason;
if your hand comes off
of the Idol
at any time for any reason;
or if your second hand
touches the Idol
or the post
that it's sitting on,
you're out of the game.
Last person left standing
wins immunity.
Guaranteed a spot
in the Final Two
and a chance
to face your jury.
And you decide who sits
next to you
at that final Tribal Council.
All right.
Take off your shoes
and any other clothing items
or necklaces you don't want on
during this.
Take your spot on the perch.
All right, challenge has begun.
Coming up on 30 minutes.
Not much of a breeze, is there?
Mm-mm.
Got a lively group
here today.
The final
immunity challenge.
JEFF:
One hour in.
Give me a status report.
What's hurting the most, Jenna?
The back foot.
It's just about trying
to switch positions up
without lifting your foot,
without sending yourself
off balance.
How are you doing,
Boston Rob?
Good.
Amber?
Jenna, how long you
think you can go?
However long these two go.
Really?
One minute after that.
Game is on.
It's a million dollars.
So... game is on.
I got a cramp.
ROB:
Uh-oh.
Jenna has a cramp.
Two hours, guys.
Two hours, 108 degrees.
Jenna...
you lifted your foot.
I lifted my foot?
You lifted
your back foot.
I thought I had
the front of my foot on.
I'm sorry, Jenna.
You're out.
Just like that, we're down
to Boston Rob and Amber.
I want the immunity.
You've had it
a million times.
A million times.
Okay.
Wait, wait, wait.
Catch me up.
What's going down?
You're going to give her
immunity and step off?
I'm going to take you,
no matter what.
Right.
Let's fight it out, anyway.
Okay.
Damn you.
JEFF:
Trust coming up.
No, it's not...
If it's not trust,
one of you would step off.
It's not trust.
It's just that...
I hate giving up.
Do you think this will
play a factor in who wins?
If somebody earned immunity,
or if somebody gave it up?
No, I just think like
the whole...
the whole game, we had
an alliance since day one.
And we stuck together
the whole time.
And every single challenge
we did,
we always gave 100%, always.
We didn't even discuss
if it came down to this.
We did talk about this.
You're saying we didn't,
but we did.
That we'd would take
each other, no matter what.
No, we talked about if
we were the last two,
would one of us step down?
Mm...
Briefly, but we did.
You wouldn't want me
to just let you win.
You'd want
to beat me,
right?
I just want to win.
Honestly.
Well, you're going
to have to beat me, then.
Oh, that's nice.
I thought about doing
that a couple times,
but I don't know if I
was big enough to reach.
You can reach.
I can only reach...
JEFF:
Uh! Amber, you're out.
I touched it.
Good going.
You know what you did?
Yeah, I touched this.
Stopped thinking
for two seconds.
I did.
You're out.
Just like that, Boston Rob,
you have final immunity.
Get over here.
It's nicely done.
You wanted to earn it,
you earned it.
The last time--
immunity.
You're going
to the Final Two.
And tonight at Tribal,
you will decide
if indeed it's going
to be Amber--
maybe there's a change
of heart--
Jenna ends up there.
All right, guys,
grab your stuff,
head back to camp.
I'll see you at Tribal
in a little bit.
JENNA:
You know I wanted
to win today.
I gave up everything
with Rupert,
and I could have picked
rocks yesterday,
and maybe Rob
would have gone.
But I lifted my damn foot,
so I blew it.
I had a million-dollar
check written in my hand
'cause I would have brought
Boston Rob--
I would have won.
And it all comes down
to me lifting my foot up.
My daughter's going
to be very proud.
So my game's over.
Boston Rob won immunity,
he's going to bring Amber,
which strategically
might not be the best bet,
you know, I think she's going
to annihilate him in the vote.
He'd have a better chance
against me,
but he won't see that.
He's giving his girlfriend
a million dollars.
That's a pretty good boyfriend.
Are you serious?
It's not that I don't
believe you...
Oh, my God.
Do you know for sure?
If you were
in my position,
you'd have, like,
a scared feeling, too.
Let me tell you
something for sure,
100% I'm
taking you. Okay?
AMBER:
I feel 99% sure
that I'm going to the Final Two
with Rob.
But I have seen him turn
on people out here.
I have seen him break his word
to people out here.
Clean up the
attitude, will ya?
AMBER:
I just can't help
but feel nervous.
ROB:
All of a sudden I guess
I can't think too clearly
trying to realize
if what I've been doing
this whole time has been
the right thing.
Is my head clouded,
is my judgment bad?
I'm not sure where
my odds are better.
Amber played a solid game,
but Amber did ride
my coattails the entire way.
I don't know,
maybe she conned me
the whole way.
Maybe it's the biggest scam
in the history of Survivor.
If I go with Jenna,
maybe more people are annoyed
at Jenna.
But then I look like a complete
ass because I'll sell out
absolutely anybody
to win this game.
I don't know if I can or cannot
win against either one of them.
I keep changing my own mind
50 times a day.
I'm going to think about it,
you know.
And I'm going
to make the decision
that I feel most
comfortable with...
based on me,
not based on morals,
not based on an alliance
that I should
or shouldn't honor.
A million dollars...
What would you do
for a million dollars?
Now bring in our jury,
Lex, Kathy,
Alicia, Shii Ann,
Big Tom and Rupert--
voted out at the last
Tribal Council.
Long day.
Started early,
had an emotional
morning,
then you had your last
immunity challenge,
where it was hot.
And it was
purely endurance.
Jenna, you were first off.
What happened?
I don't know.
You said my foot moved
off the peg.
Yeah, it was very
subtle, definitely.
I'm sure.
Frustrating?
More frustrating
that it didn't even come down
to me, like, falling off
or getting too tired
or anything like that.
So that's frustrating.
So, Jenna's first off.
It comes down to Amber
and Boston Rob,
and immediately
both of you guys
look at each other
and say, "Let's make a deal."
But a deal never
ended up happening.
Amber, was that because
this is a game that
has a trust issue?
I will not deny
that nerves were definitely
taking play
and definitely
thinking,
I would feel much
better walking
in tonight with the necklace
on and being in control
instead of letting
him be in control.
JEFF:
Rob, was that any part
of your decision
not to step off?
That, "What if I do
and she turns on me
and takes Jenna instead?"
It had to go through
your head a little bit.
Yeah, of course it
went through my mind.
I mean, how
can it not?
You can tell,
even at this
stage,
still there's paranoia.